anyahindmarch.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy | Anya Hindmarch

### About Anya Hindmarch

We are A.S.H.S. Limited trading as Anya Hindmarch, a company registered in England and Wales. Our company registration number is 03142746 and our registered office is at The Stable Block, Plough Brewery, 516 Wandsworth Road, London, SW8 3JX. Our registered VAT number is 461 5721 53. 

### What Personal Information do we collect from you?

We collect and process the following types of personal information: Title, first name, last name, email address, phone number, postal address, date of birth, previously purchased items, items you are interested in, returned items, bespoke personalisation you’ve created, payment information such as credit card details, demographic information, device ID, IP address, future communication preferences and any other information that you consider necessary to provide to us. 

We collect this data when: 

  * You make a purchase in store
  * You attend one of our events
  * You fill in a sign-up form in one of our stores
  * You make an online purchase
  * You browse and use our website
  * You fill in a sign-up form on our website
  * You fill out a questionnaire or survey that we have created
  * You view our online advertising
  * You call us
  * You use our mobile apps

The information that we collect from you online will be combined with information you may have given us in store to ensure that the data we hold about you is up-to-date. 

All personal information you supply to us will be treated in accordance with the Data Protection Act (1998) and the General Data Protection Regulations (2018). 

### How and why do we use your data?

We use your personal data to do the following: 

  * To carry out our contractual obligations arising from contracts that we enter in to with you, for example to process and deliver an online purchase to you.
  * To comply with our legal obligations arising from contracts that we enter in to with you. For example, keeping records of transactions for VAT reporting purposes.
  * To respond to any enquiries you make.
  * To help us identify you and accounts that you hold with us.
  * To provide you with information about other products and services we offer that we think you might be interested in.
  * To personalise our website, online advertising and email communications to you, to offer you a more relevant shopping experience.
  * To measure and understand how our customers interact with us, through data analysis, data aggregation and customer profiling.
  * To detect, prevent and identify fraud.

###  What is the legal basis for us processing your data?

#### Contracts

When you make a purchase from us, we will process your data to fulfil our contractual obligations for the contract that we have entered in to. For example, using your address to deliver an online purchase to you. 

####  Legal Obligation

When you make a purchase from us, we will process your data to fulfil the legal obligations that we are bound to comply with, such as tax reporting for VAT purposes. 

####  Legitimate Interest

When you make a purchase from us, we will process your data under the basis of legitimate interest. Legitimate interest is the interest of our company to conduct and manage our business and provide you with the best and most secure customer experience possible. When we process your information under legitimate interest, we take care to balance our actions with your rights and interests under data protection law. 

We may choose to send you marketing communications on the basis of legitimate interest. You will be given the right to opt-out of these communications i) when you first enter in to the contract i.e. make a purchase and ii) at any time afterwards by contacting assistant@anyahindmarch.com or writing to us at the address provided below. 

We may also use your data under legitimate interest to perform data analysis of our customers, to help us understand how our customers interact with us, and to provide you with a better customer experience. 

We may use your data to ensure the smooth and secure running of our website, for example through website analytics and fraud checks at the time of an online purchase. 

We will always keep your data secure and in accordance with the details contained in this policy. 

####  Consent

If you have shared your information with us through a sign-up form on our website, an in-store sign-up form or by subscribing to our newsletter at an event, you have provided consent for us to process your data and use it in the ways described in this privacy policy. The terms under which you are providing consent (for example this document) will be available for you to read at the time of signing up. 

You can withdraw this consent at any time by contacting assistant@anyahindmarch.com or by using the links provided in our email communications. 

###  What marketing communications can you expect from us?

Where we have consent or a legitimate interest to do so, we may use your personal information to contact you via email, social media or text message for the following: To welcome you to Anya Hindmarch and tell you more about our brand. To provide you with information relating to a purchase you have made with us. For example, other associated products that may be of interest to you. To tell you more generally about our products, services and events that we think you may be interested in. To tell you about news related to our stores, if we feel this is relevant to you and you have demonstrated an interest in receiving information relating to that store. For example, by sharing your details with that store. 

The above marketing communications are in addition to transactional messages you may receive from us regarding a purchase or return, which we will send to you to perform our contractual obligations, such as sending you an email receipt of an in-store purchase or an online purchase. 

We will always work to ensure you only receive a reasonable quantity of marketing communications from us and that these are as relevant as possible to you. 

We will never share your personal information with any other organisation for the purposes of marketing, unless we obtain your explicit prior consent. 

You can withdraw this consent at any time by contacting assistant@anyahindmarch.com or by using the links provided in our email communications. 

####  How do we ensure your data is kept secure?

We will endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect your personal data, including the use of encryption technology. However, we cannot guarantee the security of any data you disclose online. You accept the security risks of being and transacting online and will not hold us responsible for any breach of security, unless we have been negligent or in willful default. 

We use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to protect your data on our website. Click on the padlock at the top of your browser to find more information on SSL digital certificate registration. You will also notice that the URL of our websites begins with 'https:' instead of the normal 'http:'. This means that the data transmitted to and from our website and you is encrypted. 

To help ensure that your shopping experience is safe, simple and secure, Anya Hindmarch uses Adyen to process online payments. To find more information on Adyen please [ click here](https://www.adyen.com/). To ensure that your credit, debit or charge card is not being used without your consent, we will validate the name, address and other personal information supplied by you during the order process against appropriate third party databases. By accepting these terms and conditions you consent to such checks being made. In performing these checks, personal information provided by you may be disclosed to a registered Credit Reference Agency which may keep a record of that information. This is only used to confirm your identity, a credit check will not be performed and your credit rating will be unaffected. All information provided by you will be treated securely and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. 

###  When does your information go outside the EU? 

Occasionally for the purposes of executing our contractual obligations, our legitimate interests or following your consent, we may share your data with our service providers who process that data outside of the EU. For example, we may share data with our IT and delivery service providers. 

If we do share your data with organisations who process it outside of the EU, we ensure safeguards are in place to protect your data and use data protection clauses to protect your privacy. 

You can find more information about this here <http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087>

###  What are your rights when it comes to personal data? 

#### The right to access your data

You have the right to request copies of any personal information we hold about you. 

Before we release the copies to you, we will need to get proof of identity from you so we can be sure we’re giving it to the right person. 

#### The right to correct your data

If you have any changes to your personal data or you think anything we hold about you is incorrect, please let us know so that we can rectify it. You can also update your personal details by logging into My Account. 

#### The right to erase your data

You have the right to ask us to delete all the personal information we hold about you. We will action this request as quickly as possible . Unless we’re required to keep your data for any legal obligations. For example, we must keep some personal information for up to 6 years to meet HMRC requirements. If you ask us to delete your data we will do so as quickly as we can and within 30 days of receiving your request. 

If you request that we delete your data, we will keep the minimum amount of data required to make sure that you aren’t contacted by us again. 

####  The right to restrict how we use your data

If you believe that the data we hold about you is inaccurate or we are not using it for the reasons described in this policy, you can request to restrict how we use your personal data.

#### The right to data portability

You can ask us to send you the personal information we hold about you or to transfer it to a third party.

We will provide the data we have in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format (such as a CSV file) which we will either send directly to you or pass to another data controller at your request.

#### The right to object

You have the right to object to how we use your personal data. You can opt out of marketing communications at any time by contacting our Customer Services team at assistant@anyahindmarch.com or by visiting the Personal Data section of My Account. There is also an unsubscribe link at the bottom of every email we send you.

To make your experience with us the best it can be, we try to personalise the content and offers we send to you by looking at your purchase and browsing history. If you don’t want us to use your personal data for any profiling then please contact us at dataofficer@anyahindmarch.com. 

#### Data retention

We will never keep your data for any longer than we need to for the reasons listed in this Privacy Policy, unless we are legally required to do so. If you do not interact with us for a reasonable length of time, we may contact you to check that you still want to hear from us.

### Contacting us about personal data

If you wish to exercise any of the rights listed above or have any questions about them, please email us at dataofficer@anyahindmarch.com or write to us at: 

Data Officer  
Anya Hindmarch  
The Stable Block  
Plough Brewery  
516 Wandsworth Road  
London  
SW8 3JX  

We will always do our best to get a satisfactory resolution to any query or concern you have about how we use your personal data. However, if you are unhappy with the way your request is handled by us you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office. 

### Protecting children’s data

We do not knowingly collect or store any personal information from children under the age of 16. 

If you are concerned that any child under 16 who is in your care has provided us with personal information, please contact us at dataofficer@anyahindmarch.com. 

### Cookie Policy

#### What is a Cookie?

A cookie is a piece of information that is stored on your computer's hard drive by your web browser, which tracks how you use websites. Like other websites, we use cookies, web beacons and other technologies (we will refer to these collectively as ‘cookies’ throughout this guide) to improve your on-site experience. 

To enable us to monitor and improve our website, cookies gather certain aggregated information about you as you browse, including details of your operating system, browser version, domain name and IP address, the URL you visited us from, the URL you go to and the parts of the website you visit.

We use cookies only to store information such as your User ID and your session identifiers and password, to enable us to identify whether you are registered on the website and to shortcut your access to the site and any products. We will only read cookies from the cookie file placed during your web browser’s interaction with the website. 

We use a variety of cookies on the Anya Hindmarch website, these include: analytical cookies, functionality cookies and targeting and advertising cookies. For more information on the different types of cookies please visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. 

#### Why are Cookies useful?

Cookies help us to provide you with the best possible online experience by doing the following: 

  * They help us to recognise you on our website, so we can recommend products we think you’ll like and show you the information we think you’ll be interested in seeing.
  * They help us to analyse how visitors use our website, so that we can improve the online experience.
  * We can remember your specified preferences, such as the currency that you prefer to shop in.
  * They help us to keep track of items stored in your shopping basket.
  * They can make your shopping experience safer.
  * They enable us to remind you about products you have shown an interest in.

#### Cookies & Internet Advertising

By visiting the Anya Hindmarch website with your device set to accept cookies, you are consenting to the way we use our cookies, both on our website and via other means of keeping in touch with you, such as social media and through our newsletter.

To disable cookies or receive cookie notifications please follow this [link](https://www.google.com/search?q=how%20to%20disable%20cookies) for further instructions. 

###  Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may need to change this privacy policy from time to time, if our business changes and there are changes to the way we process data. If we make any important changes to the policy, we may also contact you to let you know. 

The current version of this document (V1.00) was published on 25th May 2018.
